		"< rdf : Description rdf : about = '' '' xmlns : xmp = `` http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/"" xmlns : dc = `` http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"" xmlns : xmpMM = `` http://ns.adobe.com/xap/1.0/mm/"" xmlns : pdf = `` http://ns.adobe.com/pdf/1.3/"" > 2017-12-09T20 : 48-05:00 2017-12-09T20:46:30 - 05:00 2017-12-09T20 : 48-05:00 Adobe Acrobat 7.0 xml Naval Documents of the American Revolution Volume 4 American Theater : Feb. 19 "	" 1776 -- Apr. 17 "	1776	" European Theater : Feb. 1 "	" 1776 -- May 25 "	1776	" American Theater : Apr. 18 "	" 1776 -- May 8 "	" 1776 uuid : f5dcb9cb-8bd2-4e20-ba68-e1c233b06c2d uuid : 9512c36a-bc28-4df9-bc3c-ed814f1bd1c0 Adobe Acrobat 7.0 Paper Capture Plug-in NAVAL DOCUMENTS OF The American Revolution NAVAL DOCUMENTS OF The American Revolution VOLUME 4 AMERICAN THEATRE : Feb. 19 "	" 1776-Apr ."													
																								
		17	" 1776 EUROPEAN THEATRE : Feb. 1 "	" 1776-May 25 "	" 1776 AMERICAN THEATRE Apr. 18 "	" 1776-May 8 "	1776																	
"WILLIAM BELL CLARK"	"PERSON"		" Editor For and in Collaboration with The"																					
"U.S. Navy Department With"	"ORGANIZATION"	"a Foreword by - SECRETARY OF THE"																						
"NAVY"	"ORGANIZATION"	"JOHN H. CHAFEE And an Introduction by REAR ADMIRAL"																						
"ERNEST"	"PERSON"	0																						
																								
		"`"																						
"MCNEILL ELLER"	"PERSON"																							
"U.S.N."	"LOCATION"	"-LRB- Ret . -RRB-"																						
																								
		"Director of Naval History"																						
"WASHINGTON"	"LOCATION"	": 1969 L.C.Card No. 64-60087 MARllvF rnR?S APR as 19 ' "	" ~ i REFEiGki "	0																				
																								
		"ui : si ~ ~ iaM For sale by the Superintendent of Documents "																						
"U.S. Government Printing Office Washington"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"D.C."	"LOCATION"	"20402 - Price $ 14.25 NAVAL HISTORY DIVISION SENIOR EDITORIAL STAFF Rear Admiral"																						
"Ernest McNeiIl Eller"	"PERSON"																							
"U.S.N."	"LOCATION"	"-LRB- Ret . -RRB-"																						
																								
		"Rear Admiral"																						
"F. Kent Loomis"	"PERSON"																							
"U.S.N."	"LOCATION"	"-LRB- Ret . -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"William James Morgan"	"PERSON"		" Ph.D. ."																					
																								
		"ILLUSTRATIONS AND CHARTS Commander"																						
"V. James Robison"	"PERSON"																							
"U.S.N.R."	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
																								
"NAVY"	"ORGANIZATION"	"'S ADVISORY COMMITTEE ON NAVAL HISTORY"																						
"Samuel Flagg Bemis"	"PERSON"	"-LRB- Emeritus -RRB- Elm &"																						
"L. Kayser James P. Baxter"	"PERSON"		" I11"																					
"John Haskell Kemble Francis L. Berkeley"	"PERSON"		" Jr. ."																					
																								
																								
"Leonard W. Labaree Julian P. Boyd Richard W. Leopold Marion V. Brewington Allan Nevins Jim Dan Hill Walter Muir Whitehill"	"PERSON"	"SPECIAL CONSULTANTS FOR"																						
"NAVAL"	"ORGANIZATION"	"DOCUMENTS OF THE AMERICAN REVOLUTION"																						
"L. H. Butterfield Oliver Wendell Holmes Howard H. Peckham"	"PERSON"	"I believe that the time is near when the Americans will be their own masters ."																						
																								
																								
"Caron"	"PERSON"	"de Beaumarchais 1776 Heaven seems now to ojer us the glorious privilege ... of being the Guardians of the Rights of Man - kind ... Major"																						
"NAVY"	"ORGANIZATION"	"WASHINGTON March 3 "	" 1969 FOREWORD On 13 October 1775 the"																					
"Continental Congress"	"ORGANIZATION"	"authorized the first two ships of the"																						
"Navy"	"ORGANIZATION"	0																						
																								
		"From this small beginning we have seen the country 's"																						
"Navy"	"ORGANIZATION"	"grow into a most powerful force for the security of our nation ."																						
																								
		"It has also continued "	" as it began "	" as a force for the defense of freedom-our own and that of our allies "	" who are united to us by the sea only if we keep strong on it ."																			
																								
		"In this valuable documentary series "	" through the words of participants and eye witnesses "	" we read of a small"																				
"Continental Naval"	"ORGANIZATION"	"force which promptly challenged"																						
"Britain"	"LOCATION"	"'s absolute control of the sea ."																						
																								
		"Our first amphibious expedition landed in the"																						
"Bahamas"	"ORGANIZATION"	"3 March 1776 "	" and captured gravely needed munitions "	" proving to the foe that the infant"																				
"American Navy"	"ORGANIZATION"	"was a threat to be reckoned with ."																						
																								
		"Likewise we read in this volume how the tight siege by Gen - eral"																						
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	"'s army forced the British garrison out of"																						
"Boston"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"Yet because the"																						
"Royal Navy"	"ORGANIZATION"	"controlled the sea "	" the troops embarked in their transports and sailed away without loss under the guns of the"																					
"Royal Navy"	"ORGANIZATION"	0																						
																								
		0																						
																								
		"Where or when they would come over the hori - zon to strike again from the sea anywhere down the long coast "	" no one could predict with certainty ."																					
																								
		"But with their powerful fleets it was clear they would strike again and soon ."																						
																								
		"From the letters and other documents in these pages we can also sense the quickening of the Revolution and inexorable march toward the Declaration of Independence - and in time to the entry of"																						
"France"	"LOCATION"																							
"Spain"	"LOCATION"	"and"																						
"Holland"	"LOCATION"	"to turn the conflict into the fourth World War of the 18th century ."																						
																								
		"As our nation approaches the two hundredth anniversary of its birth "	" this series emphasizes once again the unchanging significance of seapower ."																					
																								
		"3n Memoriam On 31 October 1968 "	" when this Volume was still in page proof "																					
"William Bell Clark"	"PERSON"	"left his typewriter "	" beloved manuscripts "	" and notes for the last time ."																				
																								
		"He never awakened from that evening 's sleep but instead quietly embarked upon the great Joyage beyond earth 's last horizon ."																						
																								
		"His was a full and satisfying life of devoted work and marked achievement ."																						
																								
		"Mr."																						
"Clark"	"PERSON"	"'s unique knowledge of early naval history and his great industry will be sorely missed "	" and will be an inspiration to those of us who carry forward this monumental series ."																					
																								
		"Nothing but death shall stay me ."																						
																								
																								
"Julius Caesar"	"PERSON"		" IV "	" 3 ."																				
																								
		"INTRODUCTION `` No man is an island unto himself '' in this age of satellite communication "	" jet aircraft and intercontinental missiles ."																					
																								
		"Yet even in the 18th century "	" as the documents in this volume point up "	" the Ear reaching sea made the affairs of the small emerging American nation in some ways the affairs of all ."																				
																								
		"The spark of liberty could not have survived in"																						
"America"	"LOCATION"	"without extensive aid from overseas ."																						
																								
		"Among the many significant events in these nautical pages "	" none had greater impact than"																					
"France"	"LOCATION"	"'s secret policy to prolong the war through undercover aid that could come only by sea and lvould eventually involve her powerful fleets to bring victory ."																						
																								
		"It is interesting that at the outset Bourbon autocracy promoted Ameri - can freedom-fanning the fires that would spread to"																						
"France"	"LOCATION"	"and destroy the monarchy ."																						
																								
		"Surely"																						
"Providence"	"LOCATION"	"works in mysterious and unforeseen ways - as"																						
"America"	"LOCATION"	"experienced often during the Revolution and in the stirring years to come when this land of freedom has become a beacon of hope to all men ."																						
																								
		"The initial decision to include foreign documents relating to the war at sea seems more than ever justified as we get deeper into the years of con - flict ."																						
																								
		"They bring breadth of perspective "	" significance and deeper meaning ."																					
																								
		"At the same time the growing sea of documents has vastly increased our task of selection ."																						
																								
		"It has taken four broad-beamed volumes to reach to the first months of the second year of the Revolution ."																						
																								
		"Documents printed in the volumes contain the principal "	" but by no means all the large holdings collected in the"																					
"Naval History Division"	"ORGANIZATION"	"for this period ."																						
																								
		"Through drastic editorial review "	" extracting or eliminating material "	" and footnote references "	" we have been able to extend the time span of Volume 4 over that covered in Volume 3 ."																			
																								
		"We will hold this course of selection even more closelv in sub - sequent volumes ."																						
																								
		"The wholehearted support of libraries "	" historical societies "	" museums "	" archives "	" other depositories "	" and private collectors and researchers in the"																	
"United States"	"LOCATION"	"and abroad continues to make this work a reality ."																						
																								
		"Unpub - lished Crown copyright material in the publib"																						
"Record Office"	"ORGANIZATION"	"is reproduced by permission of the"																						
"Controller of H.M. Stationery Office"	"ORGANIZATION"	0																						
																								
		"We were able to get this great editorial project underway a decade ago because of the knowledge and dedication of"																						
"William Bell Clark"	"PERSON"	0																						
																								
		"In his heart was an abiding love for the American Revolution as affected by naval events ."																						
																								
		"In his mind he had stored information from a lifetime of research and reading ."																						
																								
		"In his library he had tens of thousands of pages of transcripts relating to the Revolution ."																						
																								
		"Therefore "	" when he quietly sailed on into vaster seas we suffered a grievous loss indeed in a splendid American "	" an esteemed friend "	" and an editor whose knowledge can not be fully replaced by any man alive ."																			
																								
		"We will carry on this series but will not cease to think of him and miss him ."																						
																								
		"Within the Naval History Division the key to this project 's success and steady progress continues to be the intelIigent know-how "	" intense interest "	" and hard work of Dr. ?"																				
																								
																								
"Villiam James Morgan"	"PERSON"	"and his devoted crew in our Historical Research Section-Lieutenant"																						
"Patrick A. Lyons"	"PERSON"		" Mr."																					
"Robert I. Campbell"	"PERSON"		" Mr. and Mrs."																					
"Henry J. Scheffenacker"	"PERSON"		" Mrs."																					
"Eleanor Roll"	"PERSON"																							
"Yeo"	"PERSON"	"- man First Class"																						
"Joseph V. Eckert"	"PERSON"		" Miss"																					
"Anne Kenenski"	"PERSON"		" and a talented part time worker in our vineyard "	" Mr. arti in"																				
"Petersilia"	"PERSON"	0																						
																								
		"Lieutenant"																						
"Raymond P. Schmidt"	"PERSON"	"and Chief"																						
"Personnelman George K. McCuistien"	"PERSON"		" on summer"																					
"Naval Reserve"	"ORGANIZATION"	"duty with us "	" made significant con - tributions ."																					
																								
		"Mr."																						
"W. Bart Greenwood"	"PERSON"																							
"Navy Department Librarian"	"ORGANIZATION"		" and Miss"																					
"Mary Pickens"	"PERSON"	"did a fine job with the maps as did Mr."																						
"Charles R. Haberlein Jr."	"PERSON"		" of the Curator 's Branch "	" with other illustrations ."																				
																								
																								
"France"	"LOCATION"	"'s secret decisions that highlight the importance of the sea for the future of"																						
"America"	"LOCATION"	"represent only a small portion of the material in Volume 4 that points up this unchanging verity in history of the sea 's mighty role ."																						
																								
		"For example "	" on one day in 1776 "	" 19 April "	" the first anniversary of the embattled patriots ' stand at"																			
"Lexington"	"LOCATION"	"and"																						
"Concord"	"ORGANIZATION"		" we find these wide spread indications : a ."																					
																								
																								
"Virginia"	"LOCATION"	"newspaper reported that two British tenders sailed up the"																						
"James River"	"LOCATION"	"and captured a vessel `` with about 200 barreIs of flour on board . ''"																						
																								
		"b ."																						
																								
																								
"Pennsylvania"	"LOCATION"	"decided to build an additional Aoating battery to cover the water approaches to"																						
"Philadelphia"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"c ."																						
																								
																								
"New York"	"LOCATION"	"directed her sloop"																						
"Montgomery"	"PERSON"	"to hasten to sea to `` act against the enemies of the"																						
"United Colonies"	"ORGANIZATION"	". ''"																						
																								
		"d ."																						
																								
																								
"Massachusetts"	"LOCATION"	"named `` five armed Vessels now building '' - In-dependence "	" Rising Empire "	" Republic "	" Freedom "	" and Tyranni-cide ."																		
																								
		"e ."																						
																								
																								
"Halifax"	"LOCATION"																							
"Nova Scotia"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"Vice Admiral"																						
"Shuldham"	"PERSON"	"wrote an urgent dispatch to the Admiralty ."																						
																								
																								
"H.M.S. Glasgow"	"LOCATION"	"had arrived much `` shattered '' having `` off"																						
"Rhode Island"	"LOCATION"	"fallen in with and been attack 'd by several Armed Vessels of the Rebels . ''"																						
																								
		"f ."																						
																								
																								
"London"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"Admiralty Secretary"																						
"Philip Stephens"	"PERSON"	"had no way of knowing that"																						
"Boston"	"LOCATION"	"was recently evacuated as he addressed an order to"																						
"Shuldham"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"He urged extreme vigilance in protecting homeward-bound"																						
"West Indies"	"LOCATION"	"trade "	" and that British Captains `` take or destroy any Rebel1 Cruizers they may happen to meet with . ''"																					
																								
		"Throughout the ~ volume these "	" and many other documents "	" as President"																				
"Kennedy"	"PERSON"	"wrote in the Foreword to Volume 1 "	" `` make ` amply clear the criti - cal role played by sea power in the achievement of American independence . ''"																					
																								
																								
"E. M. Eller"	"PERSON"	"xii EDITOR 'S PREFACE Several of the most significant events of the war for independence appear in the pages of this "	" the fourth volume of ~ Naval Documents of the Ameri-can Revolution ."																					
																								
		"Foremost are the resolves of the"																						
"Continental Congress"	"ORGANIZATION"	"establishing a definite naval policy ."																						
																								
		"Operations of all war vessels "	" whether"																					
"Continental"	"ORGANIZATION"		" those under General"																					
"Washington"	"LOCATION"		" or those of the Colonies "	" had been limited to protection of ports and coastal waters "	" and capture of British ships of war or any vessel carrying troops "	" munitions "	" supplies or provisions to the enemy ."																	
																								
		"But "	" in March 1776"																					
"Congress"	"ORGANIZATION"	"authorized commis - sioning of privateers -LRB- letters of marque and reprisal -RRB- and allowed unre-stricted capture of any vessel of any description carrying the English flag ."																						
																								
		"In early April"																						
"Congress"	"ORGANIZATION"	"implemented this action through specific instruc - tions to its commanders on land and sea "	" and to each of the thirteen c010 - nies ."																					
																								
		"Second in importance "	" and following along a month later "	" was"																				
"George"	"PERSON"	"111 's proclamation banning all commerce with his rebellious colonies under the Prohibitory Act ."																						
																								
		"This "	" also "	" provided for unrestricted warfare against his disobedient subjects in"																				
"North America"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"Thirdly is the `` Considerations on the Affair of the English Colonies in"																						
"America"	"LOCATION"		" '' by the"																					
"Count de Vergennes"	"ORGANIZATION"	0																						
																								
		"In a document intended primarily for the eyes of his Spanish counterpart "	" the French Foreign Minister set forth the aims of the two Courts-prolong the war for at least a year by continuing surreptitious aid to the British colonies in"																					
"America"	"LOCATION"		" assure"																					
"Great Britain"	"LOCATION"	"at the same time that they ardently desired peace "	" and make no treaty with the Americans until the latter had declared independence and had demonstrated ability to maintain it ."																					
																								
		"`` Because a year gained "	" '' wrote Ver - gennes "	" `` for measures of vigour and foresight "	" may "	" in many respects "	" change the aspect of affairs . ''"																	
																								
		"Resolves and pronouncements "	" however "	" are but a small "	" though con - sequential part of this volume ."																			
																								
		"The first"																						
"Continental Fleet"	"ORGANIZATION"	"made a success - ful amphibious assault on"																						
"New Providence"	"LOCATION"		" in the"																					
"Bahamas"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
																								
"Commodore Hopkins"	"ORGANIZATION"	"' ships carried off the island governor "	" cannon "	" and stores "	" but a bungle denied the American raiders any sizeable quantity of the garrison 's gunpowder ."																			
																								
		"All this is described in letters and other documents "	" along with accounts of the inexperienced Fleets ' rather ignominious encounter with"																					
"H.M.S. Glasgow"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"xiii Two more vessels were added to the"																						
"Continental Navy"	"ORGANIZATION"	"in this same period : ship Reprisal and brig"																						
"Lexington"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"Early cruises of the latter are related "	" including the sharp engagement with and capture of"																					
"H.M. Sloop Edward"	"PERSON"	": `` We shattered her in a terrible manner as you will see . ''"																						
																								
		"Likewise "	" these pages reveal the building progress of some of the thirteen frigates authorized earlier by"																					
"Congress"	"ORGANIZATION"		" as well as the expansion of the navies of six of the colonies-Massachusetts "																					
"Connecticut"	"LOCATION"																							
"Pennsylvania"	"LOCATION"																							
"Maryland"	"LOCATION"		" Vir - ginia "	" and"																				
"South Carolina"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"The British side.of the picture during the months covered in this vol - ume is amply depicted ."																						
																								
		"Letters and ships ' journals tell of frustration in the attempt to recover all of the rice ships in"																						
"Savannah"	"LOCATION"	"harbor "	" of the futile effort to ascend the"																					
"Cape Fear River"	"LOCATION"	"and join force with the"																						
"Scotch Tories"	"ORGANIZATION"	"already defeated at"																						
"Moore 's Creek"	"LOCATION"	"bridge "	" of the storms that delayed the arrival of the naval and military expedition against the Southern colonies "	" of the evacuation of"																				
"Boston"	"LOCATION"	"and sailing of the British army to"																						
"Halifax"	"LOCATION"		" and of the lone success "	" relief of Quebec and rout of the bedraggled American besiegers ."																				
																								
		"It was during this period that"																						
"Congress"	"ORGANIZATION"	"sent"																						
"Silas Deane"	"PERSON"	"as its first envoy to"																						
"France"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
																								
"Deane"	"PERSON"	"went armed with contracts for the military stores it was hoped he could obtain from the French court "	" or profit-minded French merchants ."																					
																								
		"His instructions and his difficulties in getting clear of the American coast are set forth in considerable detail ."																						
																								
		"At the same time "	" is des - cribed how"																					
"Richard Lord Howe"	"PERSON"	"was cajoled by the King to take command of the British fleet ."																						
																								
																								
"Howe"	"PERSON"	"was the third admiral to attempt the impossible task of stopping the flow of powder and arms from"																						
"Europe"	"LOCATION"	"and the"																						
"West Indies"	"LOCATION"	"to the American fighting forces ."																						
																								
		"Twice the enemy probed the defenses of American ports ."																						
																								
		"One was an abortive raid by a sloop-of-war into upper"																						
"Chesapeake Bay"	"LOCATION"		" and the other an engagement-in the"																					
"Delaware River"	"LOCATION"	"between two British frigates and"																						
"Penn"	"LOCATION"	"- sylvania row galleys ."																						
																								
		"The first day of this inconclusive battle brings Volume 4 to a close ."																						
																								
		"The editorial policy followed in this documentary series is detailed in Volumes 1 and 2 ."																						
																								
		"The editor wishes to repeat his sincere appreciation to the individuals and depositories whose cooperation has made possible the com - pleteness of these hefty volumes "	" and to the zeal of those listed in Admiral"																					
"Eller"	"PERSON"	"'s introductions in this and preceding volumes "	" for supplying the `` bookmaking and infinite labors to make the series as accurate and useful as possible . ''"																					
																								
																								
"William Bell Clark"	"PERSON"	"xiv DEPOSITORY LOCATION ABBREVIATIONS ' AAS AHN AMAE AN APL APS Bda ."																						
																								
		"Arch ."																						
																								
		"BHS BM BPL ChHS CL ConnHS ConnSL CUL CWM DAC DARL DCL DLAR DUL EI FDRL HCL HH HL HSD HSP"																						
"Worcester"	"LOCATION"																							
"Massachusetts Archivo Histbrico Nacional"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Madrid Archives Du Ministhe Des Affaires Btranghres"	"LOCATION"																							
"Paris Archives Nationales"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Paris Service"	"ORGANIZATION"	"historique de la"																						
"Marine Archives du Port de Lorient"	"LOCATION"																							
"Lorient"	"LOCATION"																							
"Philadelphia Bermuda Archives "	" Hamilton "	" Bermuda Beverly Historical Society"	"ORGANIZATION"																					
"Beverly"	"LOCATION"																							
"Massachusetts British Museum"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"	"I"																						
"Boston Public Library"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Boston Chicago Historical Society"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Ann Arbor Connecticut Historical Society"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Hartford Connecticut State Library"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Hartford Columbia University Library"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"New York College of William and Mary"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Williamsburg"	"LOCATION"																							
"Virginia Dominion -LRB- Public -RRB- Archives of Canada "	" Ottawa Daughters of the American Revolution Library"	"ORGANIZATION"		" Washing - ton "																				
"D.C. Dartmouth College Library"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Hanover"	"LOCATION"																							
"New Hampshire David Library of the American Revolution"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Washington Crossing"	"LOCATION"																							
"Pennsylvania Duke University Library"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Durham"	"LOCATION"																							
"North Carolina Essex Institute"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Salem"	"LOCATION"																							
"Massachusetts Franklin D. Roosevelt Library"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Hyde Park"	"LOCATION"																							
"New York Haverford College Library"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Haverford"	"LOCATION"																							
"Pennsylvania Hempstead House"	"LOCATION"																							
"New London"	"LOCATION"																							
"Connecticut Hayes Library"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Edenton"	"LOCATION"																							
"North Carolina Historical Society of Delaware "	" Wilmington Historical Society of Pennsylvania"	"ORGANIZATION"																						
"Philadelphia Harvard University Library"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Cambridge"	"LOCATION"																							
"Massachusetts"	"LOCATION"	"1 ."																						
																								
		"The list includes depositories from which manuscripts have heen used in this and previous volurnes ."																						
																								
		"Ollr collection includes materials from a number of other depositories which will appear in later volumes ."																						
																								
		"The Descriptive List of Illustrations includcs additional sources from which graphic material has been used in Volume 4 ."																						
																								
		"HUL JCBL LC MarbHS"																						
"Mass."	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"Arch ."																						
																								
		"MassHS MCL Md. ."																						
																								
		"Arch ."																						
																								
		"MdHS MeHS MHA MNHP Mor ."																						
																								
		"Arch ."																						
																								
		"NA NCDAH NHA NHCHS NHHS NHS NLCHS NMM"																						
"N.S. Arch"	"ORGANIZATION"	0																						
																								
																								
"NYHS NYPL NYSL Pa."	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"Arch ."																						
																								
		"PM PML PRO"																						
"PS PUL R.I. Arch"	"ORGANIZATION"	0																						
																								
																								
"RIHS SCHS"	"ORGANIZATION"	"S I"																						
"UNCL USNAM Henry E. Huntington Library"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"San Marino"	"LOCATION"																							
"California John Carter Brown Library"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Providence"	"LOCATION"																							
"Rhode Island Library of Congress"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Washington"	"LOCATION"																							
"D.C. Marblehead Historical Society"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Marblehead"	"LOCATION"																							
"Massa"	"PERSON"	"- chusetts"																						
"Massachusetts Archives"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Boston Massachusetts Historical Society"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Boston Marietta College Library"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Marietta"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Ohio"	"LOCATION"																							
"Maryland Archives -LRB- Hall of Records"	"ORGANIZATION"	"-RRB- "																						
"Annapolis Maryland Historical Society"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Baltimore Maine Historical Society"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Portland Marine Historical Association"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Mystic"	"LOCATION"																							
"Morristown"	"LOCATION"																							
"Winston-Salem"	"LOCATION"																							
"North Carolina National Archives"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Washington"	"LOCATION"																							
"Raleigh Nantucket Historical Association"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Nantucket"	"LOCATION"		" Massa-chusetts"																					
"New Haven Colony"	"ORGANIZATION"	"~ istorical Society "																						
"New Haven"	"LOCATION"		" Con - necticut"																					
"New Hampshire Historical Society"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Concord Newport Historical Society"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Newport"	"LOCATION"																							
"Rhode Island New London County Historical Society"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"New London"	"LOCATION"																							
"Connecticut National Maritime Museum"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Greenwich"	"LOCATION"																							
"England Nova Scotia Archives"	"LOCATION"																							
"Halifax New-York Historical Society"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"New York New York Public Library"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"New York New York State Library"	"LOCATION"																							
"Albany Pennsylvania Archives"	"LOCATION"																							
"Harrisburg Peabody Museum"	"LOCATION"																							
"Salem"	"LOCATION"																							
"Massachusetts Pierpont Morgan Library"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"New York Public Record Office"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"London Pilgrim Society"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Plymouth"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Massachusetts Princeton University Library"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Princeton"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"New Jersey Rhode Island Archives"	"LOCATION"																							
"Providence Rhode Island Historical Society"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Providence South Carolina Historical Society"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Washington"	"LOCATION"																							
"D.C. University of North Carolina Library"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Chapel Hill"	"LOCATION"																							
"North Carolina US Naval Academy Museum"	"LOCATION"																							
"Annapolis"	"LOCATION"																							
"Maryland"	"LOCATION"	"xvi CONTENTS Foreword ... ."																						
																								
		"ix Introduction ... ."																						
																								
		"xi Editor 's Preface ... ."																						
																								
		"xiii Depository Location Abbreviations ... ."																						
																								
		"xv Descriptive List of Illustrations ... ."																						
																								
		"xxi American Theatre "	" Feb. 19 "	" 1776-Apr ."																				
																								
		17	" 1776 ... 1 European Theatre "	" Feb. 1 "	" 1776-May 25 "	" 1776 ... 879 American Theatre "	0																	
																								
		"Apr. 18 "	" 1776-May 8 "	" 1776 ... 1 147 Appendices A. Merchantmen Permitted to Sail from"																				
"Rhode Island"	"LOCATION"		" March - May 1776 ... 1479 B. Journal of"																					
"Francis Boardman"	"PERSON"		" sloop Adventure ... 1485 C. Journal of the Continental Brig Andrew Doria "	" Captain"																				
"Nicholas Biddle"	"PERSON"	"... 1489 Bibliography ... 1505 Index ... 1507 xix DESCRIPTIVE LIST ILLUSTRATIONS Page `` A Map of the World "	" with the Latest Discoveries ."																					
																								
		"... 1781 . ''"																						
																								
		0																						
																								
		0																						
																								
		"Endsheets From"																						
"Samuel Dunn"	"PERSON"		" A New Atlas of the Mundane System "	" or of ... Geography and Cosmography ... "																				
"R. Sayer"	"PERSON"	"and"																						
"J. Bennett"	"PERSON"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" 1778-1 783 ."																					
																								
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"Esek Hopkins"	"PERSON"	"..."																						
"Frontispiece Mezzotint"	"ORGANIZATION"		" published by"																					
"J. M. Will"	"PERSON"	"of"																						
"Augsburg"	"LOCATION"		" after a mezzotint published by"																					
"Thomas Hart"	"PERSON"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" 1776 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of The Brit - ish Museum "																						
"London"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"British Crown Copyright . -RRB-"																						
																								
		"0 `` Sketch of the Burning of the Houses on"																						
"Dorchester Neck"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		0																						
																								
		". ''"																						
																								
		0																						
																								
		"... ."																						
																								
		"Wash drawing by"																						
"Archibald Robertson"	"PERSON"		" c. 1776 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the"																						
"Spencer Collection of the New York Public Library"	"ORGANIZATION"	0																						
																								
																								
"Astor"	"PERSON"																							
"Lenox"	"LOCATION"	"and"																						
"Tilden"	"PERSON"	"Foundations . -RRB-"																						
																								
		"`` The"																						
"Yankey"	"ORGANIZATION"	"'s Return from Camp . ''"																						
																								
		"... 26 Broadside "	" by an unidentified author and printer "	" c. 1776 "	" featur - ing a version of the song `` Yankee Doodle '' ."																			
																								
"Essex Institute"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Salem"	"LOCATION"																							
"Massachusetts"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"Philip Schuyler"	"PERSON"	"... 53 Stipple engraving "	" by"																					
"Leney"	"PERSON"		" published in The Port Folio "																					
"Phila-delphia"	"LOCATION"		" February "	" 18 10 ."																				
																								
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"Benjamin Franklin"	"PERSON"	"... 53 Line engraving "	" by"																					
"Goldar"	"PERSON"		" from"																					
"John Andrews"	"PERSON"		" History of the War with"																					
"America"	"LOCATION"	"... "																						
"J. Fielding"	"PERSON"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" 1785-86 ."																					
																								
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"Sir"																						
"Guy Carleton"	"PERSON"	"... 53 Line engraving "	" by"																					
"J. Wooding"	"PERSON"		" published in the"																					
"New London Magazine"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" June "	" 1787 ."																				
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the"																						
"Frederick S. Hicks"	"PERSON"	"Collection "																						
"Alexandria"	"LOCATION"																							
"Virginia"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"Wharton"	"PERSON"	"and ~ um ~ hre ~ s ' draft of"																						
"Continental"	"ORGANIZATION"	"Frigate Randolph "	32	" built at"																				
"Philadelphia"	"LOCATION"	"in 1776 ... : ... 65 -LRB- The"																						
"National Archives"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"Record Group 19 . -RRB-"																						
																								
		"xxi Page `` A New and Correct Chart of the Harbour of Corke ... '' ... 90 From The English Pilot ."																						
																								
		"For the"																						
"Southern Navigation"	"ORGANIZATION"	0																						
																								
		0																						
																								
		0																						
																								
																								
"J. Mount"	"PERSON"	"& T. Page "																						
"London"	"LOCATION"		" 1764 ."																					
																								
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"Henry Laurens"	"PERSON"	"... 114 Stipple engraving "	" by B. Reading after"																					
"Du SimitiPre"	"PERSON"		" published by"																					
"William Richardson"	"PERSON"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" 1783 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the Prince - ton"																						
"University Library"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Princeton"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"New Jersey"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"`` Hole in the Wall - Island of"																						
"Abaco"	"ORGANIZATION"	". ''"																						
																								
		"... "	" ... 135 Stipple engraving "	" by"																				
"Wells"	"PERSON"		" published in the"																					
"Naval Chronicle"	"LOCATION"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" June "	" 1803 ."																				
																								
		"-LRB- The"																						
"Navy Department Library"	"ORGANIZATION"		" Washing - ton . -RRB-"																					
																								
		"The"																						
"Bahamas"	"LOCATION"		" detail from `` An Index Map ."																					
																								
		0																						
																								
		0																						
																								
		"of the.West Indies ."																						
																								
		0																						
																								
		". ''"																						
																								
		"154 From"																						
"Thomas Jefferys"	"PERSON"		" The West-India Atlas "																					
"R. Sayer"	"PERSON"	"and"																						
"J. Bennett"	"PERSON"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" 1775 ."																					
																								
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"0 `` A Plan and View of the Harbour and Town of"																						
"Providence"	"LOCATION"	"'' ... 176 Manuscript map of"																						
"New Providence"	"LOCATION"	"in the"																						
"Bahamas"	"LOCATION"		" from a sur - vey by Captain"																					
"Thomas Foley"	"PERSON"		" 1765 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the"																						
"Naval Li"	"LOCATION"	"- brary "																						
"London"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"Broadside resolutions of the"																						
"Continental Congress"	"ORGANIZATION"		" March 6 "	" 1776 ."																				
																								
		"197 Concerns colonial imports and exports ."																						
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of The"																						
"New - York Historical Society"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"New York"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"A map and views of"																						
"Boston"	"LOCATION"	"and its environs ... 209 By Lieutenant"																						
"William Pierie"	"PERSON"																							
"Royal Regiment of Artillery"	"ORGANIZATION"		" 1773 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of The British Museum "																						
"London"	"LOCATION"		" British Crown Copy - right . -RRB-"																					
																								
		0																						
																								
		"`` An Exact Draught of the Island of"																						
"New Providence One of the Bahama Islands"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		0																						
																								
		". ''"																						
																								
		"... 226 Manuscript map "	" c. 1762 ."																					
																								
		0																						
																								
		"-LRB- Collections of The Library of Con - gress "																						
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"A plan of a mortar and mortar bed ... 255 Line engraving "	" from"																					
"John Robertson"	"PERSON"		" A Treatise of ... Mathe-matical Instruments ... "																					
"London"	"LOCATION"		" 1775 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- The"																						
"Navy Department Library"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"British 24 and 12 pounder cohorn mortars "	" period df George I1 ... 255 -LRB- Courtesy of the"																					
"U.S. Army Weapons Command"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"John M. Brown"	"PERSON"	"- ing Memorial Museum "																						
"Rock Island Arsenal"	"LOCATION"																							
"Rock Island"	"LOCATION"																							
"Illinois"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
																								
"U.S. Army"	"ORGANIZATION"		" Photograph . -RRB-"																					
																								
		"xxii Page `` The Harbour of"																						
"Charles Town"	"LOCATION"	"in"																						
"South-Carolina"	"LOCATION"	"... with A View of the Town ... '' ... 27 6 From The"																						
"Atlantic Neptune"	"LOCATION"																							
"J. F.W. Des Barres"	"PERSON"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" 1777 ."																					
																								
		0																						
																								
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"Tobias Furneaux"	"PERSON"	"... ."																						
																								
		"Portrait in oils "	" by"																					
"James Northcote"	"PERSON"		" c. 1780 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the Earl of"																						
"Birkenhead"	"PERSON"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"A brace of silver mounted flintlock naval officers ' pistols with spring bayonets ... ."																						
																								
		"Made by"																						
"E. F. Taylor"	"PERSON"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" c. 1775-1780 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of War - ren"																						
"M. Moore"	"PERSON"	"Collection "																						
"Ramsey"	"PERSON"																							
"New Jersey"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"`` Chart of the Entrance of"																						
"Hudson 's River"	"LOCATION"		" from"																					
"Sandy Hook"	"PERSON"	"to"																						
"New York"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		0																						
																								
		". ''"																						
																								
		"... ."																						
																								
		"From The North American Pilot "																						
"R. Sayer"	"PERSON"	"and"																						
"J. Bennett"	"PERSON"		" Lon - don "	" 1777 ."																				
																								
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"Joseph Reed"	"PERSON"	"... ."																						
																								
		"Portrait in oils "	" by"																					
"Charles Willson Peale"	"PERSON"		" 1783 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of Independence National Historical Park "																						
"Philadelphia"	"LOCATION"																							
"Pennsyl"	"LOCATION"	"- vania . -RRB-"																						
																								
		"A view of the British evacuation of"																						
"Boston"	"LOCATION"	"... "	0																					
																								
		"... ."																						
																								
		"Woodcut "	" from an unidentified German publication "	" c. 1776 ."																				
																								
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"`` The Coast "																						
"Rivers"	"PERSON"	"and Inlets of the Province of"																						
"Georgia"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		0																						
																								
		". ''"																						
																								
		"... ."																						
																								
		"From The"																						
"Atlantic Neptune"	"LOCATION"																							
"J. F. W. Des Barres"	"PERSON"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" 1780 ."																					
																								
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"Broadside critical of"																						
"William Tryon"	"PERSON"		" Royal Governor of"																					
"New York"	"LOCATION"		" March 18"	"1776 ."																				
																								
		"... -LRB- Courtesy of The"																						
"New-York Historical Society"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"New York"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"George Washington"	"PERSON"	"... ."																						
																								
		"Obverse and reverse of a gold medal "	" designed by"																					
"DuVivier"	"PERSON"	0																						
																								
		"Awarded to"																						
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	"by resolution of"																						
"Congress"	"ORGANIZATION"		" March 25 "	1776	" to commemorate the British evacuation of"																			
"Boston"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"The medal was not actually struck until some years later ."																						
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the Trustees of the"																						
"Boston Public Library"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Boston Massachusetts"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"Upper Chesapeake Bay"	"LOCATION"		" detail from `` A Chart of the Coast of"																					
"New York"	"LOCATION"																							
"New Jersey"	"LOCATION"																							
"Pennsilvania"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		0																						
																								
		". ''"																						
																								
		"... ."																						
																								
		"From The"																						
"Atlantic Neptune"	"LOCATION"																							
"J. F. W. Des Barres"	"PERSON"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" 1780 ."																					
																								
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"xxiii Page `` Plan de la Rivikre du Cap Fear ... '' ... 440 From"																						
"Neptune"	"LOCATION"	"Americo-Septentrional ... "																						
"Dbpcit des Cartes et Plans de la Marine"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Paris"	"LOCATION"		" 1778-1780 ."																					
																								
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"`` View of"																						
"Nassau"	"LOCATION"	"in the"																						
"Bahamas"	"LOCATION"	". ''"																						
																								
		"... ."																						
																								
		"Stipple engraving "	" by"																					
"T. Medland"	"PERSON"	"after"																						
"N. Pocock"	"PERSON"		" published in the"																					
"Naval Chronicle"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" December "	" 1799 ."																				
																								
		"-LRB- The"																						
"Navy De - partment Library"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"Charles Thomson"	"PERSON"	"... ."																						
																								
		"Portrait in oils "	" by"																					
"Rembrandt Peale"	"PERSON"	"after"																						
"Charles Willson Peale"	"PERSON"		" date unknown ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the"																						
"Maryland Historical Society"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Baltimore"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"Photograph courtesy of the Frick Art Reference Li - brary "																						
"New York"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"`` Sketch of the Burning destroying"																						
"Castle William"	"PERSON"	"in"																						
"Boston"	"LOCATION"	"Har - bour '' ... ."																						
																								
		"Wash drawing by"																						
"Archibald Robertson"	"PERSON"		" c. 1776 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the"																						
"Spencer Collection of the New York Public Library"	"ORGANIZATION"	0																						
																								
																								
"Astor"	"PERSON"																							
"Lenox"	"LOCATION"	"and"																						
"Tilden"	"PERSON"	"Foundations . -RRB-"																						
																								
		"`` Two favorite Songs "	" made on the Evacuation of the Town of Bos - ton "	" by the British Troops "	" on the 17th of March "	" 1776 . ''"																		
																								
		"... ."																						
																								
		"Broadside "	" by an unidentified author and printer "	" 1776 ."																				
																								
"Essex Institute"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Salem"	"LOCATION"																							
"Massachusetts"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"Inboard profile and gun deck plan of HMS Roebuck "	" 44 guns "	" launched at the"																				
"Chatham"	"LOCATION"	"dockyard on April 28 "	" 1774 ... -LRB- Courtesy of the Trustees of the"																					
"National Maritime Museum"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Greenwich"	"LOCATION"																							
"England"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"A semi-block model of HMS Centurion "	50	" 1774 ... -LRB- Courtesy of the Trustees of the"																				
"National Maritime Museum"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Greenwich"	"LOCATION"																							
"England"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"A block model of HMS Phoenix "	44	" 1759 ... -LRB- Courtesy of the Trustees of the"																				
"National Maritime Museum"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Greenwich"	"LOCATION"																							
"England"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"Swords of the Revolutionary Period ... ."																						
																								
		"Hilt detail of"																						
"Esek Hopkins"	"PERSON"	"' silver-mounted sword "	" bearing the hallmark of"																					
"Daniel Henchman"	"PERSON"																							
"Boston"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"The blade is engraved `` Esekial Hopkins Scituate '' ."																						
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of Professor"																						
"New York"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"xxiv Page Sword of Captain"																						
"Simeon Sampson"	"PERSON"																							
"Massachusetts Navy"	"ORGANIZATION"	0																						
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of"																						
"Pilgrim Hall"	"LOCATION"		" plymouth "																					
"Massachusetts"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"Two small swords "	" of a type popular for shipboard use during the eighteenth century ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of"																						
"Baltimore"	"LOCATION"																							
"Maryland"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
																								
"Smithsonian Institution Photograph"	"ORGANIZATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"James Warren"	"PERSON"	"... ."																						
																								
		"Portrait in oils "	" by"																					
"John Singleton Copley"	"PERSON"		" c. 1763-67 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the"																						
"Massachusetts"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"Bequest of"																						
"Winslow Warren"	"PERSON"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"Sir"																						
"Henry Clinton"	"PERSON"	"... ."																						
																								
		"Line engraving "	" from"																					
"James Murray"	"PERSON"		" An Impartial History of the Present War in"																					
"America"	"LOCATION"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" 1778-178 1 ."																					
																								
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"Sir"																						
"Peter Parker"	"PERSON"	"... ."																						
																								
		"Stipple engraving "	" by"																					
"Ridley"	"PERSON"		" published in the"																					
"Naval Chronicle"	"LOCATION"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" September "	" 1804 ."																				
																								
		"-LRB- The"																						
"Navy Department Library"	"ORGANIZATION"		" "																					
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"Currency of the"																						
"North Carolina Congress"	"ORGANIZATION"	"... ."																						
																								
		"Four dollar bill ."																						
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of"																						
"Tryon Palace"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"New Bern"	"LOCATION"																							
"North Carolina"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"Five dollar bill ."																						
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of"																						
"Tryon Palace"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"New Bern"	"LOCATION"																							
"North Carolina"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"Seven and one-half dollar bill ."																						
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of"																						
"Tryon Palace"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"New Bern"	"LOCATION"																							
"North Carolina"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"Twenty dollar bill ."																						
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the"																						
"North Carolina"	"LOCATION"	"State De - partment of Archives and History "																						
"Raleigh"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"Benjamin Lincoln"	"PERSON"	"... ."																						
																								
		"Portrait in oils "	" by"																					
"Charles Willson Peale"	"PERSON"		" c. 1781-82 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of Independence National Historical Park "																						
"Philadelphia"	"LOCATION"																							
"Pennsyl"	"LOCATION"	"- vania . -RRB-"																						
																								
		"Broadside resolution of the"																						
"Continental Congress"	"ORGANIZATION"		" April 3 "	" 1776 ... ."																				
																								
		"Sends blank privateer commissions to be used by local authorities ."																						
																								
		"-LRB- Curator of the"																						
"Navy Department"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"Charles Lee"	"PERSON"	"... ."																						
																								
		"Mezzotint "	" by"																					
"Thomlinson"	"PERSON"		" published by"																					
"C. Shepherd"	"PERSON"		" October 31 "	" 1775 ."																				
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of"																						
"Colonial Williamsburg"	"LOCATION"																							
"Williamshurg"	"LOCATION"		" Vir - ginia . -RRB-"																					
																								
																								
"John Glover"	"PERSON"	"... ."																						
																								
		"Pencil drawing "	" by"																					
"John Trumbull"	"PERSON"		" 1794 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of Mr."																						
"Hall Park McCullough"	"PERSON"																							
"North Bennington"	"LOCATION"																							
"Vermont"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"Photograph corn - tesy of the Frick Art Reference Library "																						
"New York"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"xxv Page `` Round robin '' signatures of the crew of the"																						
"Continental"	"ORGANIZATION"	"brig Cabot Part of the original is missing ."																						
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of The"																						
"Rhode Island Historical Society"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Providence"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"718 Broadside proclamation of Major General"																						
"Israel Putnarn"	"PERSON"		" April 8 "	" 1776 ."																				
																								
		"... Orders communication stopped between the"																						
"New York"	"LOCATION"	"shore and the British fleet ."																						
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of The"																						
"New-York Historical Society"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"New York"	"LOCATION"	"-RRB- ."																						
																								
																								
"Samuel Nicholas"	"PERSON"		" Senior Officer of the"																					
"Continental Marine Corps"	"ORGANIZATION"	0																						
																								
		0																						
																								
		"Miniature portrait "	" location unknown "	" from the Daughters of the"																				
"American Revolution Magazine"	"ORGANIZATION"		" Volume 55 "	" June "	" 1921 ."																			
																								
		"-LRB- Cour-tesy of the Daughters of the American Revolution "																						
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"Samuel Nicholas"	"PERSON"	"' commission as Captain of Marines ... -LRB- Courtesy of the"																						
"Marine Corps Museum"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Quantico"	"LOCATION"																							
"Virginia"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"`` Inventory of Stores & c taken at"																						
"Fort Nassau-March"	"ORGANIZATION"	"3 1776 '' and `` Stores & c taken at"																						
"Fort Montague"	"LOCATION"	"March 3 1776 '' ... ."																						
																								
		"An enclosure to a letter from"																						
"Esek Hopkins"	"PERSON"	"to"																						
"Jonathan Trum-bull"	"PERSON"		" April 8 "	" 1776 ."																				
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of The"																						
"Rhode Island Historical Society"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Providence"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"A view of"																						
"Port Royal"	"LOCATION"																							
"Jamaica"	"LOCATION"	"... ."																						
																								
		"Oil by"																						
"Richard Paton"	"PERSON"		" date unknown ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the Trustees of the National Maritime R/Iuseum "																						
"Greenwich"	"LOCATION"																							
"England"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"A view of"																						
"St. Eustatius"	"LOCATION"	"... Water color drawing by"																						
"A. Nelson"	"PERSON"		" 1774 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the Ne - derlandsch Historisch Scheepvaart Museum "																						
"Amsterdam"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"John Paul Jones"	"PERSON"	"... Oil miniature on cardboard "	" by"																					
"Countess Lowendahl"	"PERSON"		" 1780 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Cour - tesy of the"																						
"U.S. Naval Academy Museum"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Annapolis"	"LOCATION"																							
"Maryland"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"Joseph Hewes"	"PERSON"	"... ."																						
																								
		"Miniature portrait in oiIs "	" by"																					
"Charles Willson Peale"	"PERSON"		" 1776 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the"																						
"U.S. Naval Academy Museum"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Annapolis"	"LOCATION"																							
"Mary"	"PERSON"	"- land . -RRB-"																						
																								
		"`` Drafts of the harbour & fortress of"																						
"New London"	"LOCATION"	"in"																						
"Connecticut"	"LOCATION"	"'' ."																						
																								
		"Manuscript map "	" by"																					
"Richard Gridley"	"PERSON"		" April "	" 1776 ."																				
																								
		"-LRB- The"																						
"National Archives"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"Papers of the"																						
"Continental Congress"	"ORGANIZATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"The schooner Baltick of"																						
"Salem"	"LOCATION"																							
"Massachusetts"	"LOCATION"	"... ."																						
																								
		"Water color "	" possibly by"																					
"Ashley Bowen"	"PERSON"	"of"																						
"Marblehead"	"LOCATION"		" hlassa-chusetts "	" c. 1767 ."																				
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the Peabody Museum "																						
"Salem"	"LOCATION"																							
"Massachusetts"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"xxvi Page `` The Wise Men of"																						
"Gotham"	"LOCATION"	"and their Goose '' ... 878 Cartoon ridiculing the self-destructive policies of the British min - istry ."																						
																								
		"Engraved and published by W. ."																						
																								
																								
"Humphrey"	"PERSON"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" Feb - ruary "	" 1776 ."																				
																								
"Congress"	"ORGANIZATION"		" Washing - ton . -RRB-"																					
																								
		"`` A Chart of the"																						
"British Channel"	"ORGANIZATION"		" Comprehending The Southern Coasts of"																					
"England"	"LOCATION"	"and"																						
"Wales"	"LOCATION"	": with the Coast of"																						
"France"	"LOCATION"	"... '' ... 898-99 From"																						
"Thomas Jefferys"	"PERSON"		" The West-India Atlas "																					
"R. Sayer"	"PERSON"	"and"																						
"J. Bennett"	"PERSON"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" 1775 ."																					
																								
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"James Cook"	"PERSON"	"... 908 Portrait in oils "	" by"																					
"Nathaniel Dance"	"PERSON"		" 1776 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the Trus - tees of the"																						
"National Maritime Museum"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Greenwich Hospital Col"	"ORGANIZATION"	"- lection "																						
"Greenwich"	"LOCATION"																							
"England"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"`` A Geometrical Plan ... Of His Majesty 's Dock Yard "	" at Chat - ham ."																					
																								
		0																						
																								
		". ''"																						
																								
		"... 927 Line engraving "	" by P. C. Canot after"																					
"J. Cleveley"	"PERSON"	"and"																						
"Thomas Mil"	"PERSON"	"- ton "	" published by"																					
"Thomas Milton"	"PERSON"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" 1755 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of The British Museum "																						
"London"	"LOCATION"		" British Crown Copyright . -RRB-"																					
																								
		"`` Entrance into"																						
"Cork Harbour"	"PERSON"	". ''"																						
																								
		"... 950 Stipple engraving "	" by"																					
"Baily"	"PERSON"	"after"																						
"Pocock"	"PERSON"		" published in the"																					
"Naval Chronicle"	"LOCATION"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" May "	" 1809 ."																				
																								
		"-LRB- The"																						
"Navy Department Library"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"Charles Gravier"	"PERSON"		" Count de Vergennes ... 965 Line engraving "	" by"																				
"Vincenzo Vangelisti"	"PERSON"	"after"																						
"Antoine F. Callet"	"PERSON"		" c. 1780 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of The"																						
"Victoria"	"LOCATION"	"and"																						
"Albert Museum"	"PERSON"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"John Montagu"	"PERSON"																							
"Earl"	"PERSON"	"of Sandwich ... 972 Line ."																						
																								
		"engraving "	" published in The"																					
"European Magazine"	"ORGANIZATION"	"and"																						
"Lon - don Review"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" May "	" 1787 ."																				
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the"																						
"Frederick S. Hicks"	"PERSON"	"Collection "																						
"Alexandria"	"LOCATION"																							
"Virginia"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"George 111 ... 972 Cameo bust in white jasper ware mounted on glass "	" by"																					
"Josiah Wedgewood"	"PERSON"		" c. 1780-1800 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of The"																						
"Victoria"	"LOCATION"	"and"																						
"Albert Museum"	"PERSON"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"British Crown Copyright . -RRB-"																						
																								
		"George Germain ... 972 Line engraving "	" by"																					
"Robert Pollard"	"PERSON"		" from"																					
"James Murray"	"PERSON"		" An Im-partial History of the Present War in"																					
"America"	"LOCATION"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" 1778-1781 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the"																						
"Anne S. K. Brown"	"PERSON"	"Military Collection "																						
"Rhode Island"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"xxvii Page A rigged model of a 32 gun frigate "	" c. 1765-66 ... 983 -LRB- Courtesy of the Trustees of the"																					
"National Maritime Museum"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Greenwich"	"LOCATION"																							
"England"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"Richard Howe"	"PERSON"	"... ."																						
																								
		"Mezzotint "	" published by"																					
"J. M. Will"	"PERSON"	"of"																						
"Augsburg"	"LOCATION"		" after a mezzotint published by"																					
"John Morris"	"PERSON"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" 1777 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the"																						
"Anne S. K. Brown"	"PERSON"	"Military Collection "																						
"Rhode Island"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"Arthur Lee"	"PERSON"	"... ."																						
																								
		"Portrait in oils "	" by"																					
"Charles Willson Peale"	"PERSON"		" 1785 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of Independence National Historical Park "																						
"Philadelphia"	"LOCATION"																							
"Pennsyl"	"LOCATION"	"- vania . -RRB-"																						
																								
		"A snow lying at anchor ... ."																						
																								
		"Oil by"																						
"Charles Brooking"	"PERSON"		" 1759 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the Trustees of the"																						
"National Maritime Museum"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Greenwich"	"LOCATION"																							
"England"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"``"																						
"Baye"	"PERSON"	"et Rade de Cadis '' ... ."																						
																								
		"From"																						
"Joseph Roux"	"PERSON"																							
"Recueil Des Principaux Plans des Ports et Rades de la Mer Mediterrante"	"ORGANIZATION"		" Estraits de m.a Carte en"																					
"Douze Feuilles"	"PERSON"																							
"Y. Gravier"	"PERSON"																							
"Genoa"	"ORGANIZATION"		" 1779 ."																					
																								
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"The Admiralty "																						
"London"	"LOCATION"	"... ."																						
																								
		"Line engraving "	" by T. simpson after"																					
"S. Wale"	"PERSON"		" published in the"																					
"New London Magazine"	"ORGANIZATION"		" February "	" 1787 ."																				
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the"																						
"Fred - erick S. Hicks"	"PERSON"	"Collection "																						
"Alexandria"	"LOCATION"																							
"Virginia"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"`` The present"																						
"State of Europe & America"	"ORGANIZATION"	"... '' ... ."																						
																								
		"Cartoon from a tract entitled A Plea of the Colonies on the Char - ges Brought against Them by Lord"																						
"Mansfield"	"PERSON"	"and Others "	" pub-lished in"																					
"London"	"LOCATION"		1776	" and reprinted in"																				
"Philadelphia"	"LOCATION"		" 1777 ."																					
																								
		"The world is depicted turned backwards by events in"																						
"America"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"While"																						
"George"	"PERSON"	"I11 looks on "	" his fleet and army sail off to the Colonies "	" leaving"																				
"England"	"LOCATION"	"open to attack from"																						
"France"	"LOCATION"		" where the Gallic Cock crows lustily at his opportunity ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the"																						
"Harvard College Library"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Cambridge"	"LOCATION"																							
"Massachusetts"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"A view of the port of"																						
"Brest"	"LOCATION"	"... ."																						
																								
		"Line engraving "	" by"																					
"Gouaz"	"PERSON"	"after"																						
"Nicolas Ozanne"	"PERSON"		" date unknown ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the"																						
"MusCe de la Marine"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Paris"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"``"																						
"Noddle Island"	"LOCATION"	"or How are we decieved . ''"																						
																								
		"... ."																						
																								
		"Cartoon satirizing official British accounts of the evacuation of Bos - ton by General"																						
"Howe"	"PERSON"	"in March "	" 1776 ."																					
																								
		"Published by R4 ."																						
																								
																								
"Darly"	"PERSON"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" 1776 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of The ~ ritish Museum "																						
"London"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"Brit - ish Crown Copyright . -RRB-"																						
																								
		"xxviii Page `` A View of His Majesty 's Dock Yard at"																						
"Portsmouth"	"LOCATION"	"... '' ... 1106 Hand colored engraving "	" after"																					
"John Cleveley"	"PERSON"	"the Younger "	" pub - lished by"																					
"Carington Bowles"	"PERSON"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" 1772 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the"																						
"Anne S. K. Brown"	"PERSON"	"Military Collection "																						
"Rhode Island"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"Henry Temple"	"PERSON"																							
"Second Viscount Palmerston"	"ORGANIZATION"	"... 1 134 Portrait in oils "	" by"																					
"Angelica Kauffman"	"PERSON"		" c. 1790 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of Ad - miral of the Fleet the"																						
"Earl Mountbatten"	"PERSON"	"of"																						
"Burma"	"LOCATION"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"`` The Blessed Effects of Venality . ''"																						
																								
		"... 1142 Cartoon suggesting that the American War is supported as an op - portunity for official corruption "	" and that its chief beneficiaries are"																					
"England"	"LOCATION"	"'s enemies ."																						
																								
		"Published in the"																						
"London Magazine"	"LOCATION"		" May 1 "	" 1776 ."																				
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of The British museum "																						
"London"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"British Crown Copyright . -RRB-"																						
																								
		"List of"																						
"Esek Hopkins"	"PERSON"	"' fleet `` which attacked the"																						
"Glasgow"	"LOCATION"	"off"																						
"Rhode Island"	"LOCATION"	"6th Apr. 1776 '' ... 1158 An enclosure to a letter from Vice Admiral"																						
"Molyneux Shuldham"	"PERSON"	"to"																						
"Philip Stephens"	"PERSON"		" April 19 "	" 1776 ."																				
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the"																						
"Public Re - cord Office"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" Adm. 1/484 . -RRB-"																					
																								
		"French naval linstock "	" powder horn "	" and powder bucket "	" eighteenth century ... 1172 -LRB- courtesy of"																			
"Raoul"	"PERSON"	"and"																						
"Jean Brunon"	"PERSON"																							
"Marseille"	"LOCATION"																							
"France"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"Deck plans of HMS Syren "	" 28 guns "	" 1775 ... 1186-87 -LRB- Courtesy of the Trustees of the"																				
"National Maritime Museum"	"ORGANIZATION"		" "																					
"Greenwich"	"LOCATION"																							
"England"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"Lower"																						
"Chesapeake Bay"	"LOCATION"		" detail from `` A Chart of the Coast of"																					
"New York"	"LOCATION"																							
"New Jersey"	"LOCATION"																							
"Pensilvania"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		0																						
																								
		". ''"																						
																								
		"... 1208 From The"																						
"Atlantic Neptune"	"LOCATION"																							
"J. F. W. Des Barres"	"PERSON"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" 1780 ."																					
																								
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"`` A View of the Town & Harbour of"																						
"Halifax"	"LOCATION"		" from"																					
"Dartmouth Shore"	"ORGANIZATION"	". ''"																						
																								
		"... 1221 Aquatint "	" from The"																					
"Atlantic Neptune"	"LOCATION"																							
"J. F. W. Des Barres"	"PERSON"		" Lon - don "	" 1780 ."																				
																								
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"`` Plan of the Naval-Yard at"																						
"Halifax"	"LOCATION"	". ''"																						
																								
		"... 1247 Manuscript map "	" c. 1784 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of The British Museum "																						
"Lon - don"	"LOCATION"		" British Crown Copyright ."																					
																								
		"`` A Chart of"																						
"Delaware Bay"	"LOCATION"	"and River ... Taken from the Original Chart Published at"																						
"Philadelphia"	"LOCATION"	"by"																						
"Joshua Fisher"	"PERSON"	". ''"																						
																								
		"... 1269 Published by"																						
"William Faden"	"PERSON"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" 1776 ."																					
																								
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"xxix Page"																						
"John Carroll"	"PERSON"	"... 1291 Portrait in oils "	" by"																					
"Gilbert Stuart"	"PERSON"		" c. 1805 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of"																						
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"Sketch of the chevaux de frise in the"																						
"Delaware River"	"LOCATION"	"... ."																						
																								
		"An enclosure to a letter from Captain"																						
"Hyde Parker"	"PERSON"	"to Vice Ad - miral"																						
"Molyneux Shuldham"	"PERSON"		" April 29 "	" 1776 ."																				
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the"																						
"Public Record Office"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"London"	"LOCATION"		" Adm. 1/484 . -RRB-"																					
																								
																								
"James Josiah"	"PERSON"	"... ."																						
																								
		"Portrait in oils "	" by"																					
"Charles Willson Peale"	"PERSON"		" signed and dated 1787 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the Collection of the late"																						
"Arthur J. Sussel"	"PERSON"																							
"Philadel"	"ORGANIZATION"	"- phia "																						
"Pennsylvania"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"View of the gun deck of the brig Fair American "	" 16 ... ."																					
																								
		"Rigged model "	" c. 1778 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the"																						
"U.S. Naval Academy Museum"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Annapolis"	"LOCATION"																							
"Maryland"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"Cast : iron 24 pounder ... ."																						
																								
		"Modern model "	" based on eighteenth century ordnarice drawings ."																					
																								
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"Newport"	"LOCATION"																							
"Rhode Islana"	"LOCATION"	"... "	" ... ."																					
																								
		"Manuscript map "	" by"																					
"Ezra Stiles"	"PERSON"		" 1758 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of"																						
"Redwood Library"	"LOCATION"	"and Athenaeum "																						
"Newport"	"LOCATION"																							
"Rhode Island"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
																								
"Nicholas Biddle"	"PERSON"	"... ."																						
																								
		"Portrait in oils "	" attributed to"																					
"James Peale"	"PERSON"		" c. 1813 "	" possibly after a lost miniature by"																				
"Charles Willson Peale"	"PERSON"		" c. 1776-77 ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of Independence National Historical Park "																						
"Philadelphia"	"LOCATION"																							
"Penn"	"LOCATION"	"- sylvania . -RRB-"																						
																								
		"`` A Bird 's Eye View of the Lower town of Quebec ... '' ... ."																						
																								
		"Water color "	" by"																					
"James Hunter"	"PERSON"		" date unknown ."																					
																								
		"-LRB- Courtesy of the"																						
"Public Archives of Canada"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Ottawa"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"Extract from the court martial proceedings on the conduct of Abra - ham"																						
"Whipple"	"PERSON"		" commander of"																					
"Continental"	"ORGANIZATION"	"ship Columbus "	" held on board"																					
"Alfred"	"PERSON"		" May 6 "	" 1776 ... -LRB- The"																				
"National Archives"	"ORGANIZATION"																							
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"Papers of the"																						
"Continental Congress"	"ORGANIZATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"The Northern Colonies and the"																						
"St. Lawrence River"	"LOCATION"		" detail from `` The British Colonies in"																					
"North America"	"LOCATION"	"... '' ... ."																						
																								
		"From"																						
"William Faden"	"PERSON"		" The North American Atlas "																					
"London"	"LOCATION"		" 1777 ."																					
																								
"Washington"	"LOCATION"	". -RRB-"																						
																								
		"AMERICAN THEATRE From February 19"	1776	" to April 17"	"1776 AMERICAN THEATRE From February 19 "	1776	" to April 17 "	" 1776 SUMMARY The British still held"																
"Boston"	"LOCATION"		" but their tenure promised to come to an early end with the arrival of cannon dragged across in mid-winter from"																					
"Ticonderoga"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"General"																						
"Howe"	"PERSON"	"and Admiral"																						
"Shuldham"	"PERSON"	"were sitting uneasily under the threat of the rapidly growing"																						
"Continental Army"	"ORGANIZATION"		" which sur-rounded the closely beleaguered town "	" save for the single opening to the sea ."																				
																								
		"Finally using the mobility which naval control assured "	" the British evacu-ated"																					
"Boston"	"LOCATION"	"on March 17 and sailed for"																						
"Halifax"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"In"																						
"New York"	"LOCATION"		" Sir"																					
"Henry Clinton"	"PERSON"	"and Captain"																						
"Hyde Parker"	"PERSON"		" Jr. viewed with misgivings the sudden arrival of General"																					
"Charles Lee"	"PERSON"	"with several thou - sand men from"																						
"Connecticut"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"Then"																						
"Clinton"	"PERSON"	"departed southward "																						
"Lee"	"PERSON"	"with - drew "	" and the Tory-minded citizens breathed with relief ."																					
																								
		"In"																						
"Canada"	"LOCATION"		" a bleak winter "	" an inadequate army "	" lack of heavy cannon "	" insufficient provisions and a wounded commander had stagnated the siege of Quebec ."																		
																								
		"The senior general officer "																						
"David Wooster"	"PERSON"		" after the death of"																					
"Richard Montgomery"	"PERSON"		" had remained in"																					
"Montreal"	"LOCATION"	"despite requests from"																						
"Benedict Arnold"	"PERSON"	"to take over before Quebec ."																						
																								
		"The"																						
"Continental"	"ORGANIZATION"	"fleet under"																						
"Esek Hopkins"	"PERSON"	"had sailed from the Capes of the"																						
"Delaware"	"LOCATION"	"and launched a successful amphibious assault on New Pro- vidence in the"																						
"Bahamas"	"LOCATION"	"where cannon and a large quantity of stores were seized ."																						
																								
		"In"																						
"Congress"	"ORGANIZATION"		" one of the principal subjects in agitation was that of legalizing privateering ."																					
																								
		"Memorials and communications from individuals pressing for letters of marque and reprisal had been received "	" but no con - clusions reached ."																					
																								
		"Meanwhile "	" from most of the thirteen embattled colonies "																					
"Provincial Congresses"	"ORGANIZATION"		" Committees of Safety and private citizens dispatched unarmed vessels "	" with local produce for exchange in the foreign"																				
"West Indies"	"LOCATION"	"for car - gos of much needed gunpowder and other war material ."																						
																								
		"Another colonial governor had joined his brethren in flight from his office ."																						
																								
		"Sir"																						
"James Wright"	"PERSON"		" of"																					
"Georgia"	"LOCATION"		" had been stripped of all authority "	" and had fled to the protection of British naval vessels ."																				
																								
		"A small British naval squadron would shortly wrest eight merchant ships laden with rice from 1 AMERICAN THEATRE the"																						
"Savannah River"	"LOCATION"		" but fail to save others from being burned by the provincials ."																					
																								
		"In"																						
"South Carolina"	"LOCATION"		" defenses were being strengthened in anticipation of the threatened arrival of a strong expeditionary force from"																					
"Britain"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"Off the"																						
"North Carolina"	"LOCATION"	"coast "	" General"																					
"Clinton"	"PERSON"	"had arrived from"																						
"New York"	"LOCATION"		" and awaited the coming of the long-promised and long-delayed army ."																					
																								
		"Its failure to appear in time caused the disastrous defeat of Highlanders and Regu - lators at"																						
"Moore 's Creek Bridge"	"LOCATION"	0																						
																								
		"Lord"																						
"Dunmore"	"PERSON"	"fumed in futile arrogance in the ashes that once were"																						
"Norfolk"	"LOCATION"		" and"																					
"Robert Eden"	"PERSON"	"sat precariously in the governor 's chair at"																						
"Annap"	"LOCATION"	"- olis ."																						
																								
		"Only"																						
"Maryland"	"LOCATION"	"to this point tolerated a Royal Governor ."																						
																								
		"19 Feb. 1776 BRIGADIERGENERALDAVID WOOSTER TO MAJOR GENERAL"																						
"PHILIP SCHUYLER"	"PERSON"	"Sir"																						
"Montreal Feby"	"PERSON"	"19th 1776 ."																						
																								
		"The paymaster has arrived but has brought no hard Cash with him "	" we can buy no provisions or"																					
"Wood"	"ORGANIZATION"	"with the"																						
"Continental Currency"	"ORGANIZATION"		" yet they must be had and that before the Middle of March -LRB- after that"																					
"Time"	"ORGANIZATION"	"there will -LSB- be -RSB- no passing up and down this River for three or four Weeks -RRB- or perhaps the Expedition may fail for Want of Supplies-Flour may be purchased for 9"																						
"Livres"	"ORGANIZATION"	"per Ct - we ought to purchase a Quantity of Beef also - What we have will now soon be gone - I understand there is a Quan - tity at Tyconderoga - I think it very necessary that it should be pushed over the"																						
"Lake"	"LOCATION"	"immediately - I need sap nothing more than inform you "	" that there is not one thousand left of the Money which you sent us "	" and that will be gone in a very few Days - I hope our Friends will not suffer the Enterprize to fall thro ' for Want of it - I am told there is a Mr"																				
"Brazier"	"PERSON"	"a Gunner at Crown point "	" rvho may be doubtless spared from there and will be much wanted at"																					
"Quebec"	"LOCATION"	"- I shall be obliged to you "	" if you will he good enough to inform me whether there are not any twelve or twenty four pound Shot "	" or 8"																				
"Inch Shells"	"ORGANIZATION"	"at"																						
"Ticonderoga"	"LOCATION"	"or Crown point if there is we shall be very glad to have them sent us "	" they will be much wanted We have at"																					
"St John"	"ORGANIZATION"	"'s a 24 ib and several 12 lb Cannon and an 8 Inch Howitzer - It will not be worth while to take them to"																						
"Quebec"	"LOCATION"	"unless we have Shot 8c Shells for them I am in Haste -LSB- & c. -RSB-"																						
"Davd Wooster"	"PERSON"	"1 ."																						
																								
		"Papers CC -LRB- Letters of Major General"																						
"Philip Schuyler"	"PERSON"	"-RRB- "	153	11	17	" NA ."																		
																								
		"Monday "	" Feb. 19tl1"	"-Very cold ."																				
																								
		"The captain of the"																						
"Senegal"	"LOCATION"	"has searched the brig iiberty and does not find anything contraband "	" but will not release her till he hears from the Comrnodore at"																					
"Halifax"	"LOCATION"																							
"I. Harold A. Innis"	"PERSON"		" ed. "	" The Diary of"																				
"Simeoti Perkins"	"ORGANIZATION"		" 1766-1780 -LRB-"																					
"Toronto"	"LOCATION"		" 1948-1961 -RRB- ."																					
																								
		"I "	" 112 ."																					
																								
		"Hereafter cited as"																						
"Innis"	"PERSON"		" ed. "																					
"Perkins"	"PERSON"	"' Diary ."																						
																								
		"2 ."																						
																								
		"The journal of"																						
"H. M. Sloop Senegal"	"ORGANIZATION"	"records on Feb ~ uary 13 and 15 "	" 1776 : `` Examining the Brigg . ''"																					
																								
		"See also"																						
"Perkins"	"PERSON"	"' Diary "	" February 1 "	1776	" Volume 3 "	" 1107 ."																		
																								
		"FEBRUARY 1776 JOURNALOF H.M.S. Lively "	" CAPTAINTHOMAS BISHOP Febry 1776"																					
"Pidgeon Hill"	"PERSON"	"-LSB- Cape Ann -RSB- NW 3 or 4"																						
"Leags Mondy"	"ORGANIZATION"	"19 at 10 AM spoke with"																						
"Chace"	"PERSON"	"a Schooner from"																						
"St Domingo"	"ORGANIZATION"	"bound to"																						
"Boston"	"LOCATION"	"sent a Petty Officer & 3 Men on board her & took out the Master & five Men 1 ."																						
																								
		"PRO "	" Admiralty 511546 ."																					
																								
